const quiz = [
  
  {
    "id": 1,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The danger of volcanoes ……….. not to be taken lightly.",
    "options": ["must", "might", "has", "have"],
    "answer": "must"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Ramesh ……… here for the last seven years.",
    "options": ["worked", "is working", "has worked", "works"],
    "answer": "has worked"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Supply the correct tag for the following statement. *Let us go,* ………..",
    "options": ["shall we?", "will we?", "do we?", "don't we?"],
    "answer": "shall we?"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Two ladies had ……… hand bags stolen at the Kathmandu Mall.",
    "options": ["its", "her", "their", "they"],
    "answer": "their"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "They are as lucky as ………..",
    "options": ["we", "our", "ourselves", "us"],
    "answer": "us"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Sincere people abide ……… their promise.",
    "options": ["by", "of", "at", "on"],
    "answer": "by"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The new manager will ……… his position on August 30.",
    "options": ["take off", "take out", "take over", "take after"],
    "answer": "take over"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Choose the correct alternative for underlined phrase in the given sentence. He got a Lion's share of the profits.",
    "options": ["no share at all", "greater share of a things", "very small part", "little profit"],
    "answer": "greater share of a things"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "There is someone in the room ……….. I certainly heard a great noise.",
    "options": ["and", "but", "for", "so"],
    "answer": "for"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Neither of them ……… a problem.",
    "options": ["anticipate", "anticipates", "have anticipated", "are anticipating"],
    "answer": "anticipates"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Choose the correct passive voice for the following sentence. We celebrate Democracy Day on Falgun seven.",
    "options": [
      "Democracy Day is celebrated on Falgun seven by us.",
      "Democracy Day was celebrated on Falgun seven by us.",
      "Democracy Day has been celebrated on Falgun seven by us.",
      "Democracy Day had been celebrated on Falgun seven by us."
    ],
    "answer": "Democracy Day is celebrated on Falgun seven by us."
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "She is ……….. obedient student.",
    "options": ["an", "a", "the", "none of the above"],
    "answer": "an"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Choose the correct answer from among the given options. I don't think I ……… be able to go.",
    "options": ["will", "should", "can", "could"],
    "answer": "will"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Choose the correct single word for the group of words given below. That which cannot be divided.",
    "options": ["indelible", "indivisible", "insoluble", "indefensible"],
    "answer": "indivisible"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following words is an abstract noun?",
    "options": ["desk", "fear", "class", "needle"],
    "answer": "fear"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following words does not have a suffix?",
    "options": ["helpless", "goodness", "fearless", "courage"],
    "answer": "courage"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The opposite meaning of 'accepted' is,",
    "options": ["liked", "noted", "provided", "rejected"],
    "answer": "rejected"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Choose the word nearest in meaning to 'emulate'.",
    "options": ["Imitate", "Deny", "Discuss", "Reject"],
    "answer": "Imitate"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Choose the correct synonym for the underlined word in the following sentence. Raman is a versatile boy.",
    "options": ["bad", "clumsy", "gifted", "lazy"],
    "answer": "gifted"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Select the correct antonym for 'segregation'.",
    "options": ["appreciation", "integration", "cohesion", "co-ordination"],
    "answer": "integration"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Fill in the gap with the correct word from among the given options. The price of consumer goods ……… increasing.",
    "options": ["are", "is", "were", "has been"],
    "answer": "is"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following sentences is incorrect in terms of subject verb agreement?",
    "options": [
      "Each of the women owns her home.",
      "All of the women own their own homes.",
      "Here are two wrenches and a hammer.",
      "Here is a hammer and two wrenches."
    ],
    "answer": "Here is a hammer and two wrenches."
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following sentences has the correct use of comma (;)?",
    "options": [
      "June 27, 2018, is a day I will never forget.",
      "Some people who go to school, enjoy the social life.",
      "He was late for dinner, we decided to eat without him.",
      "We were glad to see him, because he had brought gifts."
    ],
    "answer": "June 27, 2018, is a day I will never forget."
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Choose the part participate of the verb quit.",
    "options": ["quited", "quit", "quitting", "has quit"],
    "answer": "quit"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Choose the correct alternative from among the given options. *We spent a ...... evening together.*",
    "options": ["quite", "quit", "quiet", "quitter"],
    "answer": "quiet"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following words needs capitalization?",
    "options": ["winter", "ocean", "jewish", "university"],
    "answer": "jewish"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Choose the correct preposition from among the given options. *He is occurred ...... cheating.*",
    "options": ["for", "of", "on", "in"],
    "answer": "of"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Select the correct alternative to fill in the gap in the following sentence. *He is coming here ...... six o'clock.*",
    "options": ["upon", "on", "at", "to"],
    "answer": "at"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Select the correct meaning of the idiom in, *In the good book of*",
    "options": [
      "enjoying a pleasant moment.",
      "enjoying a favour of someone.",
      "possessing a good book for reading.",
      "purchasing a good book."
    ],
    "answer": "enjoying a favour of someone."
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Fill in the gap in the following sentence from among the given options. *I am ...... tired to go any further.*",
    "options": ["to", "too", "so", "not"],
    "answer": "too"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which is the correct indirect speech for the direct speech given below? *Hari says, \"I am very happy\".*",
    "options": [
      "Hari says he is very happy.",
      "Hari says he was very happy.",
      "Hari said he is very happy.",
      "Hari said he was very happy."
    ],
    "answer": "Hari says he is very happy."
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Select the interrogative sentence from the given options below.",
    "options": [
      "Shall I see you tomorrow?",
      "He has studied English for a long time.",
      "They won't believe you.",
      "It will be dark soon."
    ],
    "answer": "Shall I see you tomorrow?"
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Put the correct verb form in the gap below. *I ...... told you earlier if I had known.*",
    "options": ["would", "would have", "had", "should"],
    "answer": "would have"
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Choose the right pronoun from the given alternatives in the following sentence. *If everybody does ...... part, the game should go smoothly.*",
    "options": ["his", "her", "his or her", "their"],
    "answer": "his or her"
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following word is an adverb?",
    "options": ["good", "bad", "well", "melt"],
    "answer": "well"
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following is the same in meaning as in the word 'obliterate' used in the passage?",
    "options": ["Wipe out", "Wipe off", "Very Literate", "Remove"],
    "answer": "Wipe out"
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following is term regarding the reasons for progress in genetic engineering?",
    "options": [
      "Poor countries need genetic information.",
      "It has become popular subject.",
      "Economically and scientifically advanced countries can provide infrastructure for such research.",
      "Human beings are interrelated in hereditary."
    ],
    "answer": "Economically and scientifically advanced countries can provide infrastructure for such research."
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "According to the passage the question of abortion is,",
    "options": ["hotly debated", "ignored", "unanswered", "undecided"],
    "answer": "hotly debated"
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following is not true about the genetic engineering?",
    "options": [
      "Acquired ability to detect disorder in unborn babies.",
      "Possibility of abuse.",
      "Increased tendency to manipulate gene cells.",
      "Acquired ability to manipulate tissue cells."
    ],
    "answer": "Increased tendency to manipulate gene cells."
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "According to the author of the passage, the present state of knowledge about heredity has made geneticists.",
    "options": ["reckless", "optimistic", "introspective", "arrogant"],
    "answer": "optimistic"
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A number is divided by 10 gives a remainder 7. If the same number is divided by 5, then what will be the remainder?",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3", "4"],
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Which one of the following value of 'n' gives the negative result on \( n^2 - 15 \)?",
    "options": ["7", "5", "3", "4"],
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If 'n' is an integer, then which one of the following expression must be even?",
    "options": ["n(n + 1)", "n^2 + 1", "n(n + 2)", "n(n + 4)"],
    "answer": "n(n + 1)"
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the sum of first five prime numbers?",
    "options": ["18", "25", "26", "28"],
    "answer": "28"
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If you save 1 paisa today, 2 paisa next day, 4 paisa the succeeding day and so on, then what is the total saving on the week?",
    "options": ["127 paisa", "64 paisa", "256 paisa", "128 paisa"],
    "answer": "127 paisa"
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the value of \(\\square \\square \\square \\square\) ? \[ n \\square 10 \]",
    "options": ["0", "-1", "1", "10"],
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If 6 is subtracted from the cube of a number and the result is 21, then what is the value of that number?",
    "options": ["2", "3", "4", "5"],
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If the product of two consecutive even number is 288, then what are these numbers from following?",
    "options": ["14, 12", "14, 16", "16, 18", "22, 24"],
    "answer": "16, 18"
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The total of ages of A and B is 3:5, if B is 8 years elder to A, then what is the age of the A?",
    "options": ["12 yrs.", "15 yrs.", "18 yrs.", "21 yrs."],
    "answer": "12 yrs."
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If the root of the equation \(x^2 - 6x + c = 0\) is 3, then what is the value of c?",
    "options": ["3", "6", "8", "9"],
    "answer": "9"
  },
  {
    "id": 51,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Which one of the following is true for the roots of the equation \(x^2 - 8x + 16 = 0\)?",
    "options": ["imaginary & unequal", "rational & unequal", "real & equal", "real & unequal"],
    "answer": "real & equal"
  },
  {
    "id": 52,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If the matrix is of order 5 x 3, then how many elements will be single column?",
    "options": ["5", "3", "4", "15"],
    "answer": "5"
  },
  {
    "id": 53,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If \(x - 5 = 1\), then what is the value of \(x + 7\)?",
    "options": ["5", "7", "8", "13"],
    "answer": "13"
  },
  {
    "id": 54,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If \(5x + 13 = 31\), what is the value of \(\\square 5x \\square 31 \\square\) ?",
    "options": ["5", "6", "7", "8"],
    "answer": "6"
  },
  {
    "id": 55,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the correct value of . \[5 \\cdot \\square 5 \\cdot 55.\]",
    "options": ["5^3", "5", "5^4", "4"],
    "answer": "5^4"
  },
  {
    "id": 56,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If \(a^x = b, b^y = c\) and \(c^z = a\), then what is the value of \(xyz\)?",
    "options": ["c", "a", "b", "1"],
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "id": 57,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If \(6p + 6q = 36\), then what is the average value of a and b?",
    "options": ["2", "3", "4", "5"],
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "id": 58,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If \(p + q = r\), then what is the average value of p, q and r?",
    "options": ["p", "q", "r", "(p+q+r)/3"],
    "answer": "(p+q+r)/3"
  },
  {
    "id": 59,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the slope of the line whose equation is \( 2x - 4y = 9? \)",
    "options": ["1", "\( \\frac{1}{2} \)", "2", "3"],
    "answer": "\( \\frac{1}{2} \)"
  },
  {
    "id": 60,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Which one of the following is correct for the acute angle of right angled triangle?",
    "options": ["complementary", "supplementary", "adjacent", "equal"],
    "answer": "complementary"
  },
  {
    "id": 61,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "There are 60 students in a class. If 60% of them are girls, then how many boys in the class?",
    "options": ["24", "36", "18", "40"],
    "answer": "24"
  },
  {
    "id": 62,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Last year Hari was 4 feet tall, and this year he is 5 feet tall. What is the percent increase of his height?",
    "options": ["10%", "15%", "20%", "25%"],
    "answer": "25%"
  },
  {
    "id": 63,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the difference between 5 of 80 and 30% of 80?",
    "options": ["12", "18", "24", "20"],
    "answer": "20"
  },
  {
    "id": 64,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The cost of 6 pens is equal to the cost of the 10 pencils. If the cost of 4 pencils is Rs. 120, then what is the cost of 4 pens?",
    "options": ["100", "200", "300", "400"],
    "answer": "200"
  },
  {
    "id": 65,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If the cost of 7 kg sugar is Rs. 210, how much sugar can be purchased for Rs. 330?",
    "options": ["11kg", "12kg", "13kg", "14kg"],
    "answer": "11kg"
  },
  {
    "id": 66,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Ganga can read 48 pages per hour. At this rate, how many pages she can read in 80 minutes?",
    "options": ["60", "72", "48", "64"],
    "answer": "64"
  },
  {
    "id": 67,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Two numbers are in the ratio of 6:7 and their sum is 117, then what are these numbers?",
    "options": ["56, 58", "63, 54", "54, 63", "48, 56"],
    "answer": "54, 63"
  },
  {
    "id": 68,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If 5:7 = 15:x, then what is the value of x?",
    "options": ["18", "21", "24", "35"],
    "answer": "21"
  },
  {
    "id": 69,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If cost price of 8 pens and selling price of 10 pens is equal, then what is loss percentage?",
    "options": ["20%", "15%", "10%", "25%"],
    "answer": "20%"
  },
  {
    "id": 70,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If the 20% discount is given on computer book costing Rs. 300, then what will be selling price?",
    "options": ["Rs. 240", "Rs. 220", "Rs. 260", "Rs. 250"],
    "answer": "Rs. 240"
  },
  {
    "id": 71,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A watch is bought at Rs. 250 and sold at Rs. 300, then what is the profit percentage?",
    "options": ["10%", "15%", "20%", "25%"],
    "answer": "20%"
  },
  {
    "id": 72,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the population doubling time if the population growth rate is 2% per anum?",
    "options": ["60 yrs.", "50 yrs.", "40 yrs.", "30 yrs."],
    "answer": "50 yrs."
  },
  {
    "id": 73,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the rate percentage per anum that a sum of money trebles itself in 25 years?",
    "options": ["2%", "4%", "6%", "8%"],
    "answer": "8%"
  },
  {
    "id": 74,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the cardinal number of a vowel set \( V = \\{a, e, i, o, u\\} \)?",
    "options": ["4", "5", "6", "7"],
    "answer": "5"
  },
  {
    "id": 75,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the minimum value of \( n(P \\cap Q)? \) When \( n(U) = 100, n(P) = 70, \) and \( n(Q) = 45? \)",
    "options": ["15", "55", "30", "45"],
    "answer": "15"
  },
  {
    "id": 76,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Which one of the following is true for prime number?",
    "options": ["no factors", "only one factor", "only two factors", "more than two factors"],
    "answer": "only two factors"
  },
  {
    "id": 77,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Which one of the following interval notation is correct for \(\\{x: 5 \\leq x \\leq 15\\}\)?",
    "options": ["[5, ∞]", "[∞, 15]", "[6, 14]", "[5, 15]"],
    "answer": "[5, 15]"
  },
  {
    "id": 78,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the value of 'x' when it is multiplied by 6 and added to 3 times its own number gives 63?",
    "options": ["6", "7", "8", "9"],
    "answer": "7"
  },
  {
    "id": 79,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the value of \( \\sqrt{\\square} \\cdot 2^7 \)",
    "options": ["20", "25", "10", "60"],
    "answer": "20"
  },
  {
    "id": 80,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the number of seconds in 13 hour?",
    "options": ["1200 sec", "2400 sec", "3600 sec", "4800 sec"],
    "answer": "4800 sec"
  },
  {
    "id": 81,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "In a kilometer race A beats B by 100 meters and B beats C by 150 meters. In the same race, by how many meters does A beats C?",
    "options": ["150 m", "100 m", "250 m", "200 m"],
    "answer": "250 m"
  },
  {
    "id": 82,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The area of 4 walls of square room is 120 m\(^2\). If the height is 5 m, then what is the area of its floor?",
    "options": ["26 m\(^2\)", "56 m\(^2\)", "25 m\(^2\)", "36 m\(^2\)"],
    "answer": "36 m\(^2\)"
  },
  {
    "id": 83,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the probability of death?",
    "options": ["1", "\(\\frac{1}{2}\)", "0", "∞"],
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "id": 84,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the chance to give the birth by a pregnant lady on Tuesday?",
    "options": ["\(\\frac{3}{7}\)", "\(\\frac{1}{7}\)", "1", "\(\\frac{1}{2}\)"],
    "answer": "\(\\frac{1}{7}\)"
  },
  {
    "id": 85,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If the BACHELOR is written as 12345678, then how will BCA be written?",
    "options": ["123", "432", "147", "132"],
    "answer": "132"
  },
  {
    "id": 86,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Which one of the following is missing alphabet in given table? | T | Q | N | | P | O | S | | M | ? | R |",
    "options": ["K", "L", "N", "O"],
    "answer": "L"
  },
  {
    "id": 87,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Saru ranks 8\(^{th}\) from the top and 20\(^{th}\) from the bottom in class, then how many students are there in class room?",
    "options": ["28", "27", "20", "29"],
    "answer": "27"
  },
  {
    "id": 88,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Find the value of 'x' in series 1, 1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, x?",
    "options": ["21", "22", "23", "20"],
    "answer": "21"
  },
  {
    "id": 89,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "How many squares in the following figure?",
    "options": ["13", "14", "15", "16"],
    "answer": "14"
  },
  {
    "id": 90,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the value of cos \( 0^9 \)?",
    "options": ["\(\\frac{1}{2}\)", "\(\\sqrt{\\frac{1}{2}}\)", "0", "1"],
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "id": 91,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "When did the new constitute of Nepal \"Nepal Ko Sambidhan\" was released?",
    "options": ["2072 Ashoj 4", "2072 Ashoj 3", "2072 Ashoj 2", "2072 Ashoj 1"],
    "answer": "2072 Ashoj 3"
  },
  {
    "id": 92,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Who is known as \"Father of Computer\"?",
    "options": ["Charles Babbage", "Bill Gates", "Mark Zuckerberg", "John V Neumann"],
    "answer": "Charles Babbage"
  },
  {
    "id": 93,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Which one of the following discipline is not awarded by noble prize?",
    "options": ["Literature", "Economics", "Physics", "Computer Science"],
    "answer": "Computer Science"
  },
  {
    "id": 94,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Which one of the following belongs to SSD?",
    "options": ["RAM", "ROM", "Cache Memory", "Mass Storage"],
    "answer": "Mass Storage"
  },
  {
    "id": 95,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Who won the FIFA World Cup 2018 held in Russia?",
    "options": ["England", "Croatia", "France", "Germany"],
    "answer": "France"
  },
  {
    "id": 96,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Which one of the following is not an output device?",
    "options": ["OCR", "Plotter", "Monitor", "Printer"],
    "answer": "OCR"
  },
  {
    "id": 97,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "What is the scientific name of human?",
    "options": ["Rana Tigrina", "Homosepian", "Felis Catus", "Rattus"],
    "answer": "Homosepian"
  },
  {
    "id": 98,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Which one of the following is the deepest river of the Nepal?",
    "options": ["Karnali", "Koshi", "Mahakali", "Gandaki"],
    "answer": "Gandaki"
  },
  {
    "id": 99,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Who was the first prime minister of Nepal?",
    "options": ["Janga Bahadur Rana", "Matrika Prasad Koirala", "Bhimsen Thapa", "Mathabar Sing Thapa"],
    "answer": "Bhimsen Thapa"
  },
  {
    "id": 100,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Who is the writer of the Nepal novel \"Basain\"?",
    "options": ["Lil Bahadur Kshetri", "Ramlal Joshi", "Gopal Prasad Rimal", "Lokendra Bahadur Chand"],
    "answer": "Lil Bahadur Kshetri"
  },
  
  {
    "id": 101,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "John ...... tennis once or twice a week.",
    "options": ["is playing usually", "is usually playing", "usually plays", "plays usually"],
    "answer": "usually plays"
  },
  {
    "id": 102,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "I would be ...... if you could send me details of your PS/Zrange.",
    "options": ["thankful", "please", "content", "grateful"],
    "answer": "grateful"
  },
  {
    "id": 103,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "What is a LAN in computer networks?",
    "options": ["Literary Area Network", "Local Area Network", "Long Area Network", "Local Asian Network"],
    "answer": "Local Area Network"
  },
  {
    "id": 104,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "I've lost one of my gloves. I ...... it somewhere.",
    "options": ["must drop", "must have dropped", "must be dropping", "must have been dropping"],
    "answer": "must have dropped"
  },
  {
    "id": 105,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "An item of data such as a number, a name, or an address is called as ......",
    "options": ["logical record", "physical record", "field", "internal schema"],
    "answer": "field"
  },
  {
    "id": 106,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "There's somebody walking behind us. I think ......",
    "options": ["we are following", "we are being followed", "we are followed", "we are being following"],
    "answer": "we are being followed"
  },
  {
    "id": 107,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The feminine gender of bachelor is called a ......",
    "options": ["spinster", "bride", "sister", "countess"],
    "answer": "spinster"
  },
  {
    "id": 108,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The police officer stopped us and asked us where ......",
    "options": ["were we going", "are we going", "we are going", "we were going"],
    "answer": "we were going"
  },
  {
    "id": 109,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The procedure for ...... a new file is very simple.",
    "options": ["create", "created", "creating", "creation"],
    "answer": "creating"
  },
  {
    "id": 110,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Call an ambulance. There's been ......",
    "options": ["accident", "an accident", "some accident", "a accident"],
    "answer": "an accident"
  },
  {
    "id": 111,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "They live on a busy road ...... a lot of noise from the traffic.",
    "options": ["It must be", "There must be", "There must have", "It must have"],
    "answer": "There must be"
  },
  {
    "id": 112,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "I don't like stories ...... have unhappy endings.",
    "options": ["that", "they", "while", "who"],
    "answer": "that"
  },
  {
    "id": 113,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The exam was quite easy ...... We expected.",
    "options": ["more easy that", "more easy than", "easier than", "easier as"],
    "answer": "easier than"
  },
  {
    "id": 114,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "You should insure your bicycle ...... stolen.",
    "options": ["in case it will be", "if it will be", "in case it is", "if it is"],
    "answer": "in case it is"
  },
  {
    "id": 115,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "I'm going away ...... the end of January.",
    "options": ["at", "on", "in", "to"],
    "answer": "at"
  },
  {
    "id": 116,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "She has learnt ...... (now she knows how to cook.)",
    "options": ["cooking", "cooked", "to cook", "to cooking"],
    "answer": "to cook"
  },
  {
    "id": 117,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The word 'Photographic' has its principal stress on the ...... syllable.",
    "options": ["1st", "2nd", "3rd", "4th"],
    "answer": "3rd"
  },
  {
    "id": 118,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "It is getting dark. We ...... a taxi.",
    "options": ["had better taken", "had better to take", "had better take", "had better took"],
    "answer": "had better take"
  },
  {
    "id": 119,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "...... you ...... had, you would have succeeded in the examination.",
    "options": ["If, had", "Had, work", "Had, worked", "If, worked"],
    "answer": "Had, worked"
  },
  {
    "id": 120,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "I bought a pen, a pencil, a sharpper and a water bottle, It has a ......",
    "options": ["Rising Tone", "Rising Tone + Falling Tone", "Falling Tone + Falling Tone", "Falling Tone + Rising Tone"],
    "answer": "Falling Tone + Rising Tone"
  },
  {
    "id": 121,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "...... tired, I went to bed early.",
    "options": ["Felt", "To fell", "Feeling", "Having to feel"],
    "answer": "Feeling"
  },
  {
    "id": 122,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The antonym of 'sharp' is",
    "options": ["slow", "blunt", "hard", "thin"],
    "answer": "blunt"
  },
  {
    "id": 123,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Please ...... enclosed our current catalogue and price list.",
    "options": ["find", "look", "receive", "examine"],
    "answer": "find"
  },
  {
    "id": 124,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "...... she has written some interesting stories.",
    "options": ["Late", "Lately", "Later", "Later"],
    "answer": "Lately"
  },
  {
    "id": 125,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "We look forward ...... from you.",
    "options": ["hear", "to hear", "hearing", "to hearing"],
    "answer": "to hearing"
  },
  {
    "id": 126,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "By next Monday, he ...... his job.",
    "options": ["will change", "will have changed", "changes", "will be changing"],
    "answer": "will have changed"
  },
  {
    "id": 127,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The negative statement of \"He used to live here.\" is ......",
    "options": ["He used not to live here", "He never used to live here", "Did he used to live here?", "both a) and b)"],
    "answer": "He used not to live here"
  },
  {
    "id": 128,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "A device moved by hand to indicate position on the screen is ......",
    "options": ["mainframe", "icon", "microchip", "mouse"],
    "answer": "mouse"
  },
  {
    "id": 129,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "...... contains all the information we need.",
    "options": ["These books", "These book", "This books", "This book"],
    "answer": "This book"
  },
  {
    "id": 130,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "…… rice that the shopkeeper showed me was of an inferior quality.",
    "options": ["The little", "A little", "Little", "Few"],
    "answer": "The little"
  },
  {
    "id": 131,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "He'd rather stay back ……?",
    "options": ["hadn't he", "didn't he", "Would not he", "wouldn't he"],
    "answer": "wouldn't he"
  },
  {
    "id": 132,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "We …… him if he treats the customers rudely.",
    "options": ["dismiss", "dismissed", "will dismiss", "would dismiss"],
    "answer": "will dismiss"
  },
  {
    "id": 133,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Should you require anything further at this time, please do not …… to contact me.",
    "options": ["void", "hesitate", "delay", "prevent"],
    "answer": "hesitate"
  },
  {
    "id": 134,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The active of: \"My money was picked yesterday\" is ……",
    "options": ["Somebody picked my money yesterday.", "Somebody had picked my money yesterday.", "Somebody picked my money.", "Somebody picked my money the other day."],
    "answer": "Somebody picked my money yesterday."
  },
  {
    "id": 135,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Of the two sisters Anu is ……",
    "options": ["taller", "tall", "the tallest", "the taller"],
    "answer": "the taller"
  },
  {
    "id": 136,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Why does the author compare 'nature' to business?",
    "options": ["Because of the capital depletion in nature and business.", "Because of the similarity with which one should use both.", "Because of the same interest level yield.", "Because of the diversity of the various capital inputs."],
    "answer": "Because of the similarity with which one should use both."
  },
  {
    "id": 137,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "\"The folly our descendants are least likely to forgive us.\" What is the business equivalent of the folly the author is referring to?",
    "options": ["Reducing the profit margin", "Not pumping some money out of profits into the business", "Eroding the capital lease of the business", "Putting interest on capital back into the business"],
    "answer": "Eroding the capital lease of the business"
  },
  {
    "id": 138,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following statements is false in context of the given passage?",
    "options": ["The diversity of plant life is essential for human existence.", "Scientists know the usefulness of most plant species.", "Chemicals for cancer treatment are available from plants.", "There are around ten times the plant species undiscovered as compared to the discovered ones."],
    "answer": "Scientists know the usefulness of most plant species."
  },
  {
    "id": 139,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following correctly reflects the opinion of the author to take care of hunger in the world?",
    "options": ["Increase the number of edible plants being cultivates.", "Increase cultivation of the 150 species presently under cultivation.", "Increase the cultivation of medical plants.", "Increase the potential of the uncultivated edible plants."],
    "answer": "Increase the number of edible plants being cultivates."
  },
  {
    "id": 140,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following is mentioned as the immediate cause for the destruction of plant species?",
    "options": ["Soil Erosion", "Destruction of habitat", "Cultivation", "Agricultural practices"],
    "answer": "Agricultural practices"
  },
  {
    "id": 141,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "For some integer m, which of the following form is odd integer?",
    "options": ["m", "m + 1", "2m", "2m + 1"],
    "answer": "2m + 1"
  },
  {
    "id": 142,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Two lines are perpendicular if the product of their slopes is",
    "options": ["0", "1", "-1", "2"],
    "answer": "-1"
  },
  {
    "id": 143,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Graphically, the pair of equations 6x-3y+10=0 and 2x-y+9=0 represents two lines which are:",
    "options": ["Intersecting at exactly one point.", "Intersecting at exactly two points.", "Coincident.", "Parallel"],
    "answer": "Parallel"
  },
  {
    "id": 144,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "In the given figure, ∠T and ∠B are right angles. If the length of AT, BC and AS are 15, 16, and 17 cm respectively, then the length of TC is:",
    "options": ["18 cm", "16 cm", "19 cm", "12 cm"],
    "answer": "18 cm"
  },
  {
    "id": 145,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If |A|=0, then A is",
    "options": ["zero matrix", "singular matrix", "non-singular matrix", "Identity matrix"],
    "answer": "singular matrix"
  },
  {
    "id": 146,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Two bicycles were sold for Rs. 3990 each, gaining 5% on one and losing 5% on the other. The gain or loss percent on the whole transaction is",
    "options": ["Neither gain nor loss", "2.5% gain", "2.5% loss", "0.25% loss"],
    "answer": "0.25% loss"
  },
  {
    "id": 147,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If 72×96=6927, 58×87=7885, then 79×86 is",
    "options": ["7689", "8976", "6897"],
    "answer": "6897"
  },
  {
    "id": 148,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A ladder 15 meters long just reaches the top of a vertical wall. If the ladder makes an angle of 60° with the wall, then the height of the wall will be",
    "options": ["7.5m", "7.7m", "8.5m", "8.8m"],
    "answer": "7.5m"
  },
  {
    "id": 149,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The famous mathematician associated with finding the sum of the first 100 natural numbers is",
    "options": ["Pythagoras", "Newton", "Gauss", "Euclid"],
    "answer": "Gauss"
  },
  {
    "id": 150,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Sum of the series 1+12+132+143+⋯+21+321+431+⋯ is",
    "options": ["1", "2", "1.555", "1.7555"],
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "id": 151,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The AM between x-3 and x+5 is",
    "options": ["2x+2", "x-1", "x+1", "2x+1"],
    "answer": "x+1"
  },
  {
    "id": 152,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The value of sin60°cos30°+sin30°cos60° is",
    "options": ["0", "1", "2", "4"],
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "id": 153,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If sinθ−cosθ=0 then the value of θ is",
    "options": ["30°", "90°", "60°", "45°"],
    "answer": "45°"
  },
  {
    "id": 154,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A TV is purchased at Rs. 5000 and sold at Rs. 4000, the loss percent is",
    "options": ["10%", "20%", "25%", "28%"],
    "answer": "20%"
  },
  {
    "id": 155,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If the cost price is 25% of selling price. Then the profit percent is",
    "options": ["75%", "200%", "300%", "25%"],
    "answer": "300%"
  },
  {
    "id": 156,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A man buys an item at Rs. 1200 and sells it at the loss of 20 percent. Then what is the selling price of that item",
    "options": ["Rs. 660", "Rs. 760", "Rs. 860", "Rs. 960"],
    "answer": "Rs. 960"
  },
  {
    "id": 157,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The mean of the data: 4, 10, 5, 9, 12 is:",
    "options": ["8", "10", "9", "15"],
    "answer": "8"
  },
  {
    "id": 158,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A dice is thrown in the air. The probability of getting odd numbers is",
    "options": ["1/2", "3/4", "3", "4"],
    "answer": "1/2"
  },
  {
    "id": 159,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If we throw two coins in the air, then the probability of getting both tails will be",
    "options": ["1/2", "1/4", "2", "4"],
    "answer": "1/4"
  },
  {
    "id": 160,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The distance of point A(2,4) from x-axis is",
    "options": ["2", "4", "6", "20"],
    "answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "id": 161,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The value of 6+6+66+6+6 is:",
    "options": ["4", "3", "3.5", "-3"],
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "id": 162,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A function f(x) is said to be an odd function if",
    "options": ["f(x)=f(x)", "f(-x)=-f(x)", "f(x)=k where k is a constant", "f(x)=k+f(x) where k is an odd number"],
    "answer": "f(-x)=-f(x)"
  },
  {
    "id": 163,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The set A=(x:x<=N and x2+3x+2=0) is",
    "options": ["Null set", "Finite set", "Infinite set", "Set with two elements."],
    "answer": "Null set"
  },
  {
    "id": 164,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The number of subsets of a set containing n elements is",
    "options": ["n²", "2n", "2n−1", "2n"],
    "answer": "2n"
  },
  {
    "id": 165,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "For a set A, (AC)C is",
    "options": ["U−A", "AC", "UC", "A"],
    "answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "id": 166,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Range of the function f(x)=x/|x| is",
    "options": ["{1}", "{1, −1}", "{0}", "(−∞, ∞)"],
    "answer": "{1, −1}"
  },
  {
    "id": 167,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The value of i−51 is",
    "options": ["1", "−1", "i", "−i"],
    "answer": "i"
  },
  {
    "id": 168,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The value of limx->0 sinx/x is",
    "options": ["0", "1", "−1", "None of these"],
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "id": 169,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Derivative of ln2x with respect to x is",
    "options": ["2x", "1/2x", "1/x", "x"],
    "answer": "1/x"
  },
  {
    "id": 170,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Value of limx->2 (x2−4)/(x−2) is",
    "options": ["0", "4", "0/0", "∞"],
    "answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "id": 171,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the area of the shaded region in the adjoining diagram?",
    "options": ["6cm²", "7cm²", "8cm²", "9cm²"],
    "answer": "6cm²"
  },
  {
    "id": 172,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A can do a piece of work in 10 days and B can do it in 15 days. How many days will it take if they work together?",
    "options": ["4", "6", "5", "7"],
    "answer": "6"
  },
  {
    "id": 173,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The solution of the equation x2+1=0 in complex number system is,",
    "options": ["1", "-1", "0", "±i"],
    "answer": "±i"
  },
  {
    "id": 174,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the value of x in equation 4x=1/4",
    "options": ["1/4", "1/2", "-1", "1"],
    "answer": "-1"
  },
  {
    "id": 175,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The value of 0! is",
    "options": ["0", "10", "1", "∞"],
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "id": 176,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If a square has side 10 cm then diagonal is:",
    "options": ["15 cm", "10√2 cm", "20 cm", "12 cm"],
    "answer": "10√2 cm"
  },
  {
    "id": 177,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If TP and TQ are the two tangents to a circle with centre O so that ∠POQ=110∘, then ∠PTQ is equal to",
    "options": ["70∘", "80∘", "90∘", "110∘"],
    "answer": "70∘"
  },
  {
    "id": 178,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Area of an equilateral triangle with side length a is equal to",
    "options": ["(√3/2)a", "(3/2)a²", "(√3/4)a²", "(3/4)a"],
    "answer": "(√3/4)a²"
  },
  {
    "id": 179,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Which function is even function?",
    "options": ["f(x)=sin√x", "f(x)=cos√x", "f(x)=x²-2x", "f(x)=e^x"],
    "answer": "f(x)=cos√x"
  },
  {
    "id": 180,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The product of a rational and an irrational number is:",
    "options": ["Always an integer", "Always a rational number", "Always an irrational number", "Sometimes rational and sometimes irrational"],
    "answer": "Always an irrational number"
  },
  {
    "id": 181,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The value of (16)^(1/2) is",
    "options": ["1/16", "1/2", "4", "1/4"],
    "answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "id": 182,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The number, (3-√3)(3+√3) is",
    "options": ["an irrational number", "a rational number", "not a natural number", "none of these"],
    "answer": "a rational number"
  },
  {
    "id": 183,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A trapezium has:",
    "options": ["One pair of opposite sides parallel", "Two pair of opposite sides parallel to each other", "All its sides are equal", "All angles are equal"],
    "answer": "One pair of opposite sides parallel"
  },
  {
    "id": 184,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the angle made by line the x+y+1=0 with x-axis?",
    "options": ["90°", "120°", "135°", "180°"],
    "answer": "135°"
  },
  {
    "id": 185,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The zero's of the quadratic equation x²-5x+6 are",
    "options": ["5 and 6", "-5 and -6", "2 and 3", "-2 and -3"],
    "answer": "2 and 3"
  },
  {
    "id": 186,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A person took a loan of Rs 1500 from his employer for 3 months at 12% per annum simple interest. The amount he has to be return is:",
    "options": ["Rs. 1500", "Rs. 1545", "Rs. 1555", "Rs. 1575"],
    "answer": "Rs. 1545"
  },
  {
    "id": 187,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If 5^(x+3)=25^x then value of x is",
    "options": ["0", "1", "2", "3"],
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "id": 188,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If x<0 then |x| is equal to",
    "options": ["-x", "x", "0", "1"],
    "answer": "-x"
  },
  {
    "id": 189,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If x+y=3 and x²+y²=5 then value of xy is",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3", "4"],
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "id": 190,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The range of the function f(x)=3x-2, is",
    "options": ["(−∞,∞)", "R={3}", "(−∞,0)", "(0,−∞)"],
    "answer": "(−∞,∞)"
  },
  {
    "id": 191,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Who is the author of the novel 'Seto Dharati'?",
    "options": ["Amar Neupane", "Subin Bhattarai", "Buddhisagar", "Jhamak Ghimire"],
    "answer": "Amar Neupane"
  },
  {
    "id": 192,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "When was Tri-Chandra College established?",
    "options": ["1985 BS", "1975 BS", "1990 BS", "2016 BS"],
    "answer": "1975 BS"
  },
  {
    "id": 193,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "What is the full form of PDF in computer file?",
    "options": ["Processed Document File", "Protected Document Format", "Partial Document File", "Portable Document Format"],
    "answer": "Portable Document Format"
  },
  {
    "id": 194,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Who was the first programmer in computer?",
    "options": ["Charles Babbage", "Lady Ada Lovelace", "Bill Gates", "John Napier"],
    "answer": "Lady Ada Lovelace"
  },
  {
    "id": 195,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "How many players are there in Cricket?",
    "options": ["6", "8", "11", "15"],
    "answer": "11"
  },
  {
    "id": 196,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Who discovered the America?",
    "options": ["Shakespeare", "Columbus", "George Washington", "Michael Goryachov"],
    "answer": "Columbus"
  },
  {
    "id": 197,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Who was the first prime minister of Nepal?",
    "options": ["Janga Bahadur Rana", "Bir Shamsher", "Bhimsen Thapa", "Tanka Prasad Acharya"],
    "answer": "Bhimsen Thapa"
  },
  {
    "id": 198,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "The recent height of Mt. Everest is:",
    "options": ["8848 m", "8840 m", "8848.86 m", "8848.42 m"],
    "answer": "8848.86 m"
  },
  {
    "id": 199,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "How many districts are there in Nepal?",
    "options": ["74", "75", "77", "76"],
    "answer": "77"
  },
  {
    "id": 200,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Which is the biggest province of Nepal?",
    "options": ["Gandaki Pradesh", "Sudhurpashchim Pradesh", "Karnati Pradesh", "Bagnati Pradesh"],
    "answer": "Karnati Pradesh"
  }



];

export default quiz;